oysterbooks.com 2015-03-18

# Oyster Privacy Policy

  * Terms of Service
  * Privacy
  * Copyright Policy
  * Payment Terms
  * Gift Terms
  * Referral Terms

Effective date: July 9, 2013

**Hi, and welcome to Oyster’s Privacy Policy.** To provide you with the best possible service, including personalized book recommendations and social features, Oyster needs to collect some information about you. In the following paragraphs, we’ll explain our policy regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of your information. We’ll also describe what types of data we gather, what we do with it, and how you can manage and control its use (as pertains to your personal information). As we update and grow our services, this Privacy Policy may change. We will notify you of changes to the Privacy Policy that we consider significant by posting a notice on the Services, but we encourage you to check back here from time to time to keep yourself apprised of any modifications.

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Studio SBV, Inc. d/b/a Oyster (“Oyster”, “we”, “our” or “us”) on the collection, use and disclosure of your information on www.oysterbooks.com (the “Site”) and the services, features, content or applications, including the Oyster mobile application (“Application”), we offer (collectively with the Site and the Application, the “Services”).

We will receive information about you in various ways and from various sources. These include: 

  1. if you register for the Site and the Services, through your user account on the Services (your “Account”)
  2. your use of the Services generally; and
  3. from third party websites and services. When you use the Services, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

##### What does this privacy policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) gathered when you are using or accessing the Services. This Privacy Policy also covers our treatment of any Personal Information that our business partners share with us or that we share with our business partners.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”) that you elect to access through the Service or to individuals that we do not manage or employ. When you click on a third party logo displayed on or in the Services, and it links you to a different website or application, you are acknowledging that our Privacy Policy no longer applies to that website or application. You must read the privacy policies of the Third Party Services to see how your personal information will be handled on such Third Party Services.

While we attempt to facilitate access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access.

In accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly solicit or accept Personal Information from users known to be under thirteen years of age. If you are under the age of thirteen, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any personal information about yourself. If we learn that we have received any Personal Information from a user under thirteen years of age, we will take appropriate steps to remove that user’s Personal Information from our records.

##### What information do we collect?

The information we gather enables us to personalize, improve and continue to operate the Services. In connection with certain aspects of the Services, we may request, collect and/or display some of your Personal Information. We collect the following types of information from our users.

###### Account information:

When you create an Account, you will provide information that could be Personal Information, such as your username, password and email address. The information we collect here will be used to process your registration, your orders and payments, and to communicate with you about these topics, among others. We may also use the e-mail address provided to send you updates about us and the Services, including news about added features, special offers and promotions, surveys, and other general correspondence about the Services. If you do not want to receive certain types of communications from us, simply adjust your e-mail preferences through your Account settings.

You acknowledge that this information may be personal to you, and by creating an account on the Services and providing Personal Information to us, you allow others, including us, to identify you and therefore may not be anonymous. We may use your contact information to send you information about our Services, but as stated above, we will contact you only rarely when we feel such information is important.

If you connect to the Services using your Facebook account, you are authorizing us to collect authentication information. This does not include your Facebook account password, but it does include your username, encrypted access credentials, and any other information that may be available on or through your Facebook account, including your name, profile picture, stated country of residence, hometown, e-mail address, date of birth, gender, and the names, pictures, and networks of your Facebook friends. We may store this information for two purposes: to personalize and improve your experience, and to verify your credentials with Facebook to ensure a smooth and optimal login flow. Your activities on Facebook are covered by the Facebook Terms and Policies. Additionally, if you connect the Services to your Twitter account, the Services will interact with Twitter in a number of ways, as described to you at the point of connection. As with Facebook, your activities on Twitter are covered by Twitter’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. We cannot and will not connect any of your accounts without your authorization.

###### User content:

Some features of the Services allow you to provide content to the Services, such as written comments. All content submitted by you to the Services may be retained by us indefinitely, even after you terminate your account. We may continue to disclose such content to third parties in a manner that does not reveal Personal Information, as described in this Privacy Policy.

###### Reading information:

We receive and record information regarding reading behavior on the services including, but not limited to, the books that users click or open, specific pages opened or read, and words displayed to end users.

###### Financial information:

We may collect financial information, such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information).  In addition, such financial information is collected and stored by our third party payment processing company (the “Payment Processor”), and use and storage of that information is governed by the Payment Processor’s applicable terms of service and privacy policy.

We may also collect some limited information related to processing your payment, such as your postal code, mobile number, and details of your transaction history with the Services. In addition, the Payment Processor may provide us with some limited information related to you, such as a unique token that enables you to make additional purchases using the information they have stored (this information may include your card’s type, expiration date, and the last four digits of your account number).

###### Information via find friends:

If you choose, you can use the Services to locate other people with Services accounts, and add them as your friends, either through (i) your contacts list (e.g., address book on your device), or (ii) through a search of e-mail addresses on the Service. If you choose to find your friends through your device's contacts list, then we will access your contacts list to determine whether or not someone associated with your contact is using the Services. If you choose to find your friends through a search of our Services then simply type an e-mail address to search and we will perform a search on our Services.

When you allow Oyster to access your contact list, the e-mail addresses in your contact list are hash encoded and sent to oyster's servers and compared to the hash-encoded email addresses of other oyster users. This process enables friends to find each other on the service. We do not store these hash-encoded email addresses. If you do not want oyster to have access to your contacts' email addresses, do not connect your contacts to Oyster using the “find friends” feature.

###### IP address information and other information collected automatically:

  * We automatically receive and record information from your web browser or device when you interact with the Services, including your IP address and cookie information. This information is used for fighting spam/malware and also to facilitate collection of data concerning your interaction with the Services (e.g., what links you have clicked on). Information that we may collect includes, without limitation: the URL you come from, the unique device ID, the network and computer performance of the device you are using, the browser type, browser language and identifying information, transactional information that enables digital rights management, the operating system you are using, the Application version, and your location information.
  * Generally, the Services automatically collect usage information, such as the number and frequency of visitors to the Site. We may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us and third parties authorized by us to figure out how often individuals use parts of the Services so that we can analyze and improve them.

###### Email communications:

We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. We use this confirmation to improve our customer service.

###### Information collected using cookies:

  * Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser when you access a website. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit the Site and otherwise use the Services through the Internet. Generally speaking, cookies make the Internet more useful by storing information about your preferences as you interact with our Services -- this helps us tailor the Services to your taste.
  * Our cookies do not, by themselves, contain Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information to tell us who you are. As noted, however, we do use cookies to identify that your web browser has accessed aspects of the Services and may associate that information with your Account if you have one.
  * Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. We strongly recommend that you leave cookies active, because they enable you to take advantage the most attractive features of the Services.
  * This Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies only and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties. We do not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer. For example, third party websites to which a link points may set cookies on your computer.
  * The Services uses analytics services, including but not limited to Google Analytics, an analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"), and Mixpanel. Google Analytics and Mixpanel use cookies to help analyze how visitors arrive at and use the Site, and provide us with statistical reports on Services activity. The information generated by the cookies or other technologies about your use of the Services (including IP address) (the “Analytics Services Information”) is transmitted to Google Analytics or Mixpanel and potentially stored on servers in the United States. Google Analytics and Mixpanel will use the Analytics Services Information to compile reports on the activity on the Services for us. The Analytics Services Information will also provide us with other services related to activity on the Services and Internet usage. Google and Mixpanel may also transfer the Analytics Services Information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the Analytics Services Information on their behalf. Google's use of the Analytics Services Information is governed by the Google Terms of Service and the Google Privacy Policy; Mixpanel's use of the Analytics Services Information is governed by the Mixpanel Terms of Use and the Mixpanel Privacy Policy. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Services. By using the Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google and / or Mixpanel in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

For more information about the use of cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org, www.youronlinechoices.eu (Europe) or www.aboutads.info/choices/ (United States). If you have any questions or comments about our use of cookies, please contact us at hello@oysterbooks.com.

###### Information related to advertising the use of web beacons:

To support and enhance the Services, we may serve advertisements, and also allow third parties to serve advertisements, through the Services. These advertisements are sometimes targeted and served to particular users and may come from third party companies called “ad networks.”  Ad networks include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms.

Advertisements served through the Services may be targeted to users who fit a certain general profile category, may be based on anonymized information inferred from information provided to us by a user, including Personal Information (e.g., gender or age), may be based on the Services usage patterns of particular users, or may be based on your activity on Third Party Services. We do not provide Personal Information to any ad networks for use outside of the Services.

To increase the effectiveness of ad delivery, we may deliver a file (known as a “web beacon”) from an ad network to you through the Services. Web beacons allow ad networks to provide anonymized, aggregated auditing, research and reporting for us and for advertisers. Web beacons also enable ad networks to serve targeted advertisements to you when you visit other websites. Because your web browser must request these advertisements and web beacons from the ad network’s servers, these companies can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from their site.

##### How, and with whom, is my information shared?

The Services are designed to help you share information with others. As a result, some of the information generated through the Services is shared publicly or with third parties. 

###### Public information about your activity on the services:

Some of your activity on and through the Services is public by default. This may include, but is not limited to, content you have posted publicly on the Site or otherwise through the Services. If you do not want your activity on the Services to be public to other users, we generally give you settings to make your information more private if you so prefer.

Registered users may have some of this information associated with their Accounts. Unregistered users will not have this association, but information concerning their use of the Services (such as what pages they have visited) may be tracked anonymously through the use of cookies and stored by us.

Please also remember that, as with many social media, publishing and content-sharing platforms, if you choose to provide Personal Information using certain public features of the Services, then that information is governed by the privacy settings of those particular features and may be publicly available. Individuals reading such information may use or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge, and search engines may index that information. We therefore urge you to think carefully about including any specific information you may deem private in content that you create or information that you submit through the Services.

###### IP address information:

While we collect and store IP address information, that information is not made public. We do at times, however, share this information with our partners, service providers and other persons with whom we conduct business, and as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy.

###### Information you elect to share:

You may access other Third Party Services through the Services, for example by clicking on links to those Third Party Services from within the Site. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these Third Party Services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding those Third Party Services’ privacy policies. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on the Services.

###### Aggregate information:

We share Aggregate Information with our partners, service providers and other persons with whom we conduct business. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners can understand how and how often people use our Services and their services or websites, which facilitates improving both their services and how our Services interface with them. In addition, these third parties may share with us non-private, aggregated or otherwise non Personal Information about you that they have independently developed or acquired.

###### Email communications with us:

As part of the Services, you may occasionally receive email and other communications from us, such as special offers we think may be of interest to you and communications relating to your Account. Communications relating to your Account will only be sent for purposes important to the Services, such as password recovery.

###### User profile information:

User profile information including your username and other information you enter may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services. Also, since all user e-mail addresses are searchable, other users of the services will be able to ascertain whether or not a person associated with an e-mail address has an Oyster account or not.

###### Financial information:

As stated above, we may collect financial information.  In addition, financial information is collected and stored by our Payment Processor. We may from time to time request and receive some of your financial information from our Payment Processor for the purposes of completing transactions you have initiated through the Services, enrolling you in discount, rebate, and other programs in which you elect to participate, protecting against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as needed to manage our business.

###### Information shared with our agents:

We employ and contract with people and other entities that perform certain tasks on our behalf and who are under our control (our “Agents”). For example, we may partner with other companies to provide infrastructure and IT services, process credit card transactions, provide customer support, analyze and enhance data, and personalize and optimize our web pages. We may need to share Personal Information with our Agents in order to provide products or services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our Agents do not have any right to use or disclose Personal Information or other information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information with our Agents.

###### Information disclosed pursuant to business transfers:

In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy.

###### Information disclosed for our protection and the protection of others:

We also reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as it reasonably believes is necessary to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (ii) enforce the Terms of Service or Payment Terms, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect our rights, property or safety, our users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

##### Is information about me secure?

Your Account information will be protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need to prevent unauthorized access to your Account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your smartphone, computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your Account. 

We seek to protect Account information to ensure that it is kept private; however, we cannot guarantee the security of any Account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

If you sell or return your smartphone or computer, it is your responsibility to log out of the Services, and to deactivate such devices before you return or sell them. If you fail to log out and deactivate such devices, subsequent users of such devices may be able to access your account information.

We otherwise store all of our information, including your IP address information, using industry-standard techniques. We do not guarantee or warrant that such techniques will prevent unauthorized access to information about you that we store, Personal Information or otherwise.

##### What information of mine can I access?

If you are a registered user, you can access information associated with your Account by logging into the Services. Registered and unregistered users can access and delete cookies through their web browser settings. 

###### California privacy rights:

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: 28 West 27th St., #10F. New York, NY 10001.

##### How can I cancel my subscription?

Should you ever decide to delete your subscription, you may do so through your Account. Given the nature of sharing on the Services, any public activity on your Account prior to deletion will remain stored on our servers and will remain accessible to the public. 

##### What choices do I have regarding my information?

  * You can always opt not to disclose certain information to us, even though it may be needed to take advantage of some of our features.

##### What happens when there are changes to this privacy policy?

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Services or sending you an email. A user is bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Services after such changes have been first posted.

##### What if I have questions or concerns?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy using the Services, please send a detailed message to us at hello@oysterbooks.com. We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.
